export const theoryQuestions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "What is the time complexity of accessing an element in an array?",
    options: ["O(1)", "O(n)", "O(log n)", "O(n^2)"],
    answer: "O(1)",
    category: "Array",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is true about arrays?",
    options: [
      "Arrays are fixed in size.",
      "Arrays allow for dynamic resizing.",
      "Arrays do not have a fixed index.",
      "Arrays are always sorted.",
    ],
    answer: "Arrays are fixed in size.",
    category: "Array",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Which operation is the most efficient in a stack?",
    options: ["Push", "Pop", "Peek", "None"],
    answer: "Push",
    category: "Stack",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What is the time complexity for the pop operation in a stack?",
    options: ["O(1)", "O(n)", "O(log n)", "O(n^2)"],
    answer: "O(1)",
    category: "Stack",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      "In a queue, which operation follows the FIFO (First In First Out) principle?",
    options: ["Enqueue", "Dequeue", "Peek", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Dequeue",
    category: "Queue",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "What is the time complexity of enqueue operation in a queue?",
    options: ["O(1)", "O(n)", "O(log n)", "O(n^2)"],
    answer: "O(1)",
    category: "Queue",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Which of the following operations can be performed on a deque?",
    options: [
      "Insert at front",
      "Insert at rear",
      "Delete from front",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
    category: "Deque",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "In a deque, the insertion and deletion operations are performed from which ends?",
    options: ["Front only", "Rear only", "Both ends", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Both ends",
    category: "Deque",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is true about linked lists?",
    options: [
      "Linked lists have a fixed size.",
      "Linked lists use contiguous memory locations.",
      "Linked lists are dynamic in size.",
      "Linked lists are slower than arrays.",
    ],
    answer: "Linked lists are dynamic in size.",
    category: "List",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "What is the time complexity of inserting a new element at the beginning of a singly linked list?",
    options: ["O(1)", "O(n)", "O(log n)", "O(n^2)"],
    answer: "O(1)",
    category: "List",
  },
];
